<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fangyi Zhou</title><link>https://fangyi.io/</link><description>Recent content on Fangyi Zhou</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fangyi.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crash-Stop Failures in Asynchronous Multiparty Session Types</title><link>https://fangyi.io/publication/2025/crash-stop-failures-in-asynchronous-multiparty-session-types/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/publication/2025/crash-stop-failures-in-asynchronous-multiparty-session-types/</guid><description>&lt;p>Session types provide a typing discipline for message-passing systems. However,
their theory often assumes an ideal world: one in which everything is reliable
and without failures. Yet this is in stark contrast with distributed systems in
the real world. To address this limitation, we introduce a new asynchronous
multiparty session types (MPST) theory with crash-stop failures, where
processes may crash arbitrarily and cease to interact after crashing. We
augment asynchronous MPST and processes with crash handling branches, and
integrate crash-stop failure semantics into types and processes. Our approach
requires no user-level syntax extensions for global types, and features a
formalisation of global semantics, which captures complex behaviours induced by
crashed/crash handling processes. Our new theory covers the entire spectrum,
ranging from the ideal world of total reliability to entirely unreliable
scenarios where any process may crash, using optional reliability assumptions.
Under these assumptions, we demonstrate the sound and complete correspondence
between global and local type semantics, which guarantee deadlock-freedom,
protocol conformance, and liveness of well-typed processes by construction,
even in the presence of crashes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What the date?</title><link>https://fangyi.io/2023/11/what-the-date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/2023/11/what-the-date/</guid><description>&lt;p>A friend of mine found out something interesting with the &lt;code>date&lt;/code> command in
coreutils:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Are these different for you too?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>$ date -d &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;a week ago&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>$ date -d &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;1 week ago&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Indeed, after trying it on my terminal, the two dates differ by one hour.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>$ date -d &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;a week ago&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Mon &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">6&lt;/span> Nov 21:51:16 GMT &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">2023&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>$ date -d &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;1 week ago&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Mon &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">6&lt;/span> Nov 22:51:18 GMT &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">2023&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>However, the results are different for my friend:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Designing Asynchronous Multiparty Protocols with Crash-Stop Failures</title><link>https://fangyi.io/publication/2023/designing-asynchronous-multiparty-protocols-with-crash-stop-failures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/publication/2023/designing-asynchronous-multiparty-protocols-with-crash-stop-failures/</guid><description>&lt;p>Session types provide a typing discipline for message-passing systems. However,
most session type approaches assume an ideal world: one in which everything is
reliable and without failures. Yet this is in stark contrast with distributed
systems in the real world. To address this limitation, we introduce Teatrino, a
code generation toolchain that utilises asynchronous multiparty session types
(MPST) with crash-stop semantics to support failure handling protocols.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We augment asynchronous MPST and processes with crash handling branches. Our
approach requires no user-level syntax extensions for global types and features
a formalisation of global semantics, which captures complex behaviours induced
by crashed/crash handling processes. The sound and complete correspondence
between global and local type semantics guarantees deadlockfreedom, protocol
conformance, and liveness of typed processes in the presence of crashes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Producing long and short versions of a paper in LaTeX</title><link>https://fangyi.io/2023/02/producing-long-and-short-versions-of-a-paper-in-latex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/2023/02/producing-long-and-short-versions-of-a-paper-in-latex/</guid><description>&lt;p>Conferences have different submission requirements for papers.
Submissions are usually subject to a page limit, but supplementary materials
(or appendices) are permitted.
Here is a guide to produce various versions of a paper in LaTeX.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="short-and-long-versions">Short and Long Versions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The easiest way is probably to produce a short version that satisfies the page
limit,
and a long version containing omitted details (usually in an appendix).
This way has the benefit that one can simply read the long version, as it
usually contains the short version in its entirely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generalised Multiparty Session Types with Crash-Stop Failures</title><link>https://fangyi.io/publication/2022/generalised-multiparty-session-types-with-crash-stop-failures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/publication/2022/generalised-multiparty-session-types-with-crash-stop-failures/</guid><description>&lt;p>Session types enable the specification and verification of communicating
systems. However, their theory often assumes that processes never fail. To
address this limitation, we present a generalised multiparty session type
(MPST) theory with crash-stop failures, where processes can crash arbitrarily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our new theory validates more protocols and processes w.r.t. previous work. We
apply minimal syntactic changes to standard session $\pi$-calculus and types:
we model crashes and their handling semantically, with a generalised MPST
typing system parametric on a behavioural safety property. We cover the
spectrum between fully reliable and fully unreliable sessions, via optional
reliability assumptions, and prove type safety and protocol conformance in the
presence of crash-stop failures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Neo-Classical Logic (SIGBOVIK 2022)</title><link>https://fangyi.io/2022/04/neo-classical-logic-sigbovik-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/2022/04/neo-classical-logic-sigbovik-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>My colleague Martin Vassor and I worked on a paper with title
&lt;em>Neo-Classical Logic&lt;/em> for &lt;a href="http://sigbovik.org/">SIGBOVIK&lt;/a> 2022&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read the paper &lt;a href="https://fangyi.io/assets/papers/neoclassical-logic.pdf">here&lt;/a> (with reviews).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this &lt;del>April Fool&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/del> paper, we explore a possible logic that encapsulates
seemingly contradictory observations in the real life.
We investigate how such contradictions can be represented in a logic, and show
its decidability.
Moreover, we prove standard theorems such as &amp;ldquo;Law of Excluded Middle&amp;rdquo;, but also
novel theorems such as &amp;ldquo;Law of Contradiction&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meta-Programming in LaTeX</title><link>https://fangyi.io/2022/03/meta-programming-in-latex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/2022/03/meta-programming-in-latex/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many researchers write paper in $\LaTeX$ because it provides a convenient macro
system that makes typesetting maths equations easy (or difficult, when it
doesn&amp;rsquo;t work).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One way to write papers in $\LaTeX$ is to use as few &amp;ldquo;advanced features&amp;rdquo; as
possible, for a vanilla experience: no fancy packages, just use the minimal
setup.
Gradually, as the paper starts to grow long, you begin to think of adding some
macros for things that are too long to type, for example:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Communicating Finite State Machines and an Extensible Toolchain for Multiparty Session Types</title><link>https://fangyi.io/publication/2021/communicating-finite-state-machines-and-an-extensible-toolchain-for-multiparty-session-types/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/publication/2021/communicating-finite-state-machines-and-an-extensible-toolchain-for-multiparty-session-types/</guid><description>&lt;p>Multiparty session types (MPST) provide a typing discipline for message passing
concurrency, ensuring deadlock freedom for distributed processes. This paper
first summarises the relationship between MPST and communicating finite state
machines (CFSMs), which offers not only theoretical justifications of MPST but
also a guidance to implement MPST in practice. As one of the applications, we
present ðœˆSCR (NuScr), an extensible toolchain for MPST-based multiparty
protocols. The toolchain can convert multiparty protocols in the Scribble
protocol description language into global types in the MPST theory; global
types are projected into local types, and local types are converted to their
corresponding CFSMs. The toolchain also generates APIs from CFSMs that
implement endpoints in the protocol. Our design allows for language-independent
code generation, and opens possibilities to generate APIs in various
programming languages. We design our toolchain with modularity and
extensibility in mind, so that extensions of core MPST can be easily integrated
within our framework. As a case study, we show the implementation of the nested
protocol extension in ðœˆSCR , to showcase our extensibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Communication-Safe Web Programming in TypeScript with Routed Multiparty Session Types</title><link>https://fangyi.io/publication/2021/communication-safe-web-programming-in-typescript-with-routed-multiparty-session-types/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/publication/2021/communication-safe-web-programming-in-typescript-with-routed-multiparty-session-types/</guid><description>&lt;p>Modern web programming involves coordinating interactions between browser
clients and a server. Typically, the interactions in web-based distributed
systems are informally described, making it hard to ensure correctness,
especially communication safety, i.e. all endpoints progress without type
errors or deadlocks, conforming to a specified protocol.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We present STScript, a toolchain that generates TypeScript APIs for
communication-safe web development over WebSockets, and RouST, a new session
type theory that supports multiparty communications with routing mechanisms.
STScript provides developers with TypeScript APIs generated from a
communication protocol specification based on RouST. The generated APIs build
upon TypeScript concurrency practices, complement the event-driven style of
programming in full-stack web development, and are compatible with the Node.js
runtime for server-side endpoints and the React.js framework for browser-side
endpoints.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Statically Verified Refinements for Multiparty Protocols</title><link>https://fangyi.io/publication/2020/statically-verified-refinements-for-multiparty-protocols/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/publication/2020/statically-verified-refinements-for-multiparty-protocols/</guid><description>&lt;p>With distributed computing becoming ubiquitous in the modern era, safe
distributed programming is an open challenge. To address this, multiparty
session types (MPST) provide a typing discipline for message-passing
concurrency, guaranteeing communication safety properties such as deadlock
freedom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While originally MPST focus on the communication aspects, and employ a simple
typing system for communication payloads, communication protocols in the real
world usually contain constraints on the payload. We introduce refined
multiparty session types (RMPST), an extension of MPST, that express data
dependent protocols via refinement types on the data types.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generating Interactive WebSocket Applications in TypeScript</title><link>https://fangyi.io/publication/2020/generating-interactive-websocket-applications-in-typescript/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/publication/2020/generating-interactive-websocket-applications-in-typescript/</guid><description>&lt;p>Advancements in mobile device computing power have made interactive web
applications possible, allowing the web browser to render contents dynamically
and support low-latency communication with the server. This comes at a cost to
the developer, who now needs to reason more about correctness of communication
patterns in their application as web applications support more complex
communication patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiparty session types (MPST) provide a framework for verifying conformance
of implementations to their prescribed communication protocol. Existing
proposals for applying the MPST framework in application developments either
neglect the event-driven nature of web applications, or lack compatibility with
industry tools and practices, which discourages mainstream adoption by web
developers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Statically Verified Refinements for Multiparty Protocols @ OOPSLA '20</title><link>https://fangyi.io/2020/03/statically-verified-refinements-for-multiparty-protocols-@-oopsla-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/2020/03/statically-verified-refinements-for-multiparty-protocols-@-oopsla-20/</guid><description>&lt;p>I presented my paper &lt;em>Statically Verified Refinements for Multiparty Protocols&lt;/em>
at &lt;a href="https://2020.splashcon.org/">OOPSLA 2020&lt;/a> this year, held virtually.
This paper is co-authored by &lt;a href="https://www.doc.ic.ac.uk/~fferre16/">Francisco Ferreira&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://researchprofiles.herts.ac.uk/portal/en/persons/raymond-hu(81400c55-0b06-4e2a-aba4-1b6593381f22).html">Raymond Hu&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.brunel.ac.uk/people/rumyana-neykova">Rumyana Neykova&lt;/a>,
and &lt;a href="http://mrg.doc.ic.ac.uk/people/nobuko-yoshida/">Nobuko Yoshida&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can find the paper &lt;a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3428216">here&lt;/a> from the
publisher (Open Access). The full version of the paper is available on arXiv at
&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.06541">2009.06541&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The video of the talk is available on
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eHhDkQusTAw">YouTube&lt;/a> (full version, 15 min),
and a short version (5 min) is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y9aVD-7KfRw">also
available&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our paper has an accompanying artifact (as a Docker image). Source codes are
available on &lt;a href="https://github.com/sessionstar/oopsla20-artifact">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://fangyi.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am currently on a career break.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previously, I worked as an Applied Scientist, then as a Software Development
Engineer at Amazon Prime Video.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I joined Amazon,
I was a PhD student at Imperial College London.
My PhD thesis title is
&lt;a href="https://fangyi.io/assets/phd-thesis.pdf">Refining Multiparty Session Types&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I use &lt;a href="http://pronoun.is/they">they/them&lt;/a> pronouns.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="some-links">Some links:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=PPEUHmwAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en">Google Scholar&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://dblp.uni-trier.de/pid/80/6096-2.html">DBLP&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ORCID: &lt;a href="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8973-0821">0000-0002-8973-0821&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://fangyi.io/fangyi.asc">GPG Public Key&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Talks</title><link>https://fangyi.io/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/talks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here are an (incomplete) list of my talks and their slides:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Generalised Multiparty Session Types with Crash-Stop Failures
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sep 2022 &amp;mdash;
&lt;a href="https://epsrc-stardust.github.io/meetings/kent22.html">Stardust Project Meeting&lt;/a>
&amp;mdash; Canterbury, UK
(&lt;a href="https://fangyi.io/assets/slides/StardustMeeting2022.pdf">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aug 2022 &amp;mdash;
&lt;a href="https://johnwickerson.github.io/cw2022.html">INI Concurrency Meeting&lt;/a>
&amp;mdash; Cambridge, UK
(&lt;a href="https://fangyi.io/assets/slides/INIConcurrencyMeeting2022.pdf">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Monitoring Protocol Conformance with Multiparty Session Types and OpenTelemetry
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sep 2021 &amp;mdash;
&lt;a href="https://www.dagstuhl.de/en/program/calendar/semhp/?semnr=21372">Dagstuhl Seminar: &lt;em>Behavioural Types: Bridging Theory and Practice&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
&amp;mdash; Virtual
(&lt;a href="https://fangyi.io/assets/slides/Dagstuhl2021.pdf">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mar 2021 &amp;mdash;
Mass Open Cloud &lt;a href="https://openinfralabs.org/telemetry/">Telemetry Working Group&lt;/a>
&amp;mdash; Virtual
(&lt;a href="https://fangyi.io/assets/slides/TelemetryWG2021.pdf">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Statically Verified Refinements for Multiparty Protocols
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Mar 2021 &amp;mdash;
&lt;a href="https://samoa.dcs.gla.ac.uk/events/viewtalk.jsp?id=17602">PLUG&lt;/a>
(Programming Language Research in Glasgow) &amp;mdash; Virtual&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nov 2020 &amp;mdash;
&lt;a href="https://2020.splashcon.org/details/splash-2020-oopsla/24/Statically-Verified-Refinements-for-Multiparty-Protocols">SPLASH 2020 -
OOPSLA&lt;/a>
&amp;mdash; Virtual
(&lt;a href="https://fangyi.io/assets/slides/OOSPLA2020.pdf">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>