<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Fangyi Zhou</title><link>https://fangyi.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Fangyi Zhou</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fangyi.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What the date?</title><link>https://fangyi.io/2023/11/what-the-date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/2023/11/what-the-date/</guid><description>A friend of mine found out something interesting with the date command in coreutils:
Are these different for you too?
$ date -d &amp;#39;a week ago&amp;#39; $ date -d &amp;#39;1 week ago&amp;#39; Indeed, after trying it on my terminal, the two dates differ by one hour.
$ date -d &amp;#39;a week ago&amp;#39; Mon 6 Nov 21:51:16 GMT 2023 $ date -d &amp;#39;1 week ago&amp;#39; Mon 6 Nov 22:51:18 GMT 2023 However, the results are different for my friend:</description></item><item><title>Producing long and short versions of a paper in LaTeX</title><link>https://fangyi.io/2023/02/producing-long-and-short-versions-of-a-paper-in-latex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/2023/02/producing-long-and-short-versions-of-a-paper-in-latex/</guid><description>Conferences have different submission requirements for papers. Submissions are usually subject to a page limit, but supplementary materials (or appendices) are permitted. Here is a guide to produce various versions of a paper in LaTeX.
Short and Long Versions The easiest way is probably to produce a short version that satisfies the page limit, and a long version containing omitted details (usually in an appendix). This way has the benefit that one can simply read the long version, as it usually contains the short version in its entirely.</description></item><item><title>Neo-Classical Logic (SIGBOVIK 2022)</title><link>https://fangyi.io/2022/04/neo-classical-logic-sigbovik-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/2022/04/neo-classical-logic-sigbovik-2022/</guid><description>My colleague Martin Vassor and I worked on a paper with title Neo-Classical Logic for SIGBOVIK 20221.
You can read the paper here (with reviews).
In this April Fool&amp;rsquo;s paper, we explore a possible logic that encapsulates seemingly contradictory observations in the real life. We investigate how such contradictions can be represented in a logic, and show its decidability. Moreover, we prove standard theorems such as &amp;ldquo;Law of Excluded Middle&amp;rdquo;, but also novel theorems such as &amp;ldquo;Law of Contradiction&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Meta-Programming in LaTeX</title><link>https://fangyi.io/2022/03/meta-programming-in-latex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/2022/03/meta-programming-in-latex/</guid><description>Many researchers write paper in $\LaTeX$ because it provides a convenient macro system that makes typesetting maths equations easy (or difficult, when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work).
One way to write papers in $\LaTeX$ is to use as few &amp;ldquo;advanced features&amp;rdquo; as possible, for a vanilla experience: no fancy packages, just use the minimal setup. Gradually, as the paper starts to grow long, you begin to think of adding some macros for things that are too long to type, for example:</description></item><item><title>Statically Verified Refinements for Multiparty Protocols @ OOPSLA '20</title><link>https://fangyi.io/2020/03/statically-verified-refinements-for-multiparty-protocols-@-oopsla-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fangyi.io/2020/03/statically-verified-refinements-for-multiparty-protocols-@-oopsla-20/</guid><description>I presented my paper Statically Verified Refinements for Multiparty Protocols at OOPSLA 2020 this year, held virtually. This paper is co-authored by Francisco Ferreira, Raymond Hu, Rumyana Neykova, and Nobuko Yoshida.
You can find the paper here from the publisher (Open Access). The full version of the paper is available on arXiv at 2009.06541.
The video of the talk is available on YouTube (full version, 15 min), and a short version (5 min) is also available.</description></item></channel></rss>